hi this is Bonnie and I'm recording from
the studio at although our insight
center I just wanted to give you a
little sense of some of the difference
that all the Laura can make and invite
you to our eight week summer soul
program through a series of short video
takes and today I want to talk about
something that all the lore has
developed over the years and that is
this notion of working directly with
view and so one of the ways that I like
to demonstrate that for people as I have
this kind of reproduction of Cola means
model of the planetary system and as
most of you probably know during total
ptolemies time there was a very big
challenge and about explaining the
movements of the planets and it was
complicated by the fact that they were
thinking of the earth as the center of a
planetary system and then they had these
complex orbits of the planets to
describe the way the planets moved in
the night sky and to make matters more
complicated they had to have a model
that explained the apparent retrograde
or backwards movements of the planets
with respect to the earth and the
observations that they were making so
Ptolemy came up with a model of the
orbits which are very quite complex and
this notion of epicycles which he
envisioned each of the planets that
distributed retrograde would go around
in their orbit but also have these at
periodic epicycles so that they would
apparently move backwards in the night
sky and so we all know today that
Turkish comes and he says well that's
all very good it certainly explains
retrograde but it's much too complex if
we think of the orbital system revolving
around the Sun then we have a much more
elegant model and so now not only is the
model more elegant but it has the
capacity to explain everything that
Ptolemy explained and much more
explanatory power so this is what we use
as an analogy to talk about the shift in
view the view from an earth centric
planetary system to a heliocentric solar
system makes a huge difference in the
history of science in our understanding
so we take this as an analogy and we use
it to develop insight training in people
and what we use it for as an analogy is
we talk about that we are all inside our
own complex lives and especially young
people today are facing a very complex
future a lot of radical change
acceleration of the institutionalization
decentralization the deconstruction of
all the knowledge systems so this is
very complex and there's a lot of
suggestions and opinions out there that
for me I like ptolemies approach just
making everything more and more more
complex and so at all the Laura we've
developed principles and practices so
when we have situations that are complex
that way we learn to situate ourselves
inside our view to identify we call it
constellated just like the solar system
constantly all the nodes all the other
features that are making the complexity
and be able to identify where we're
sitting where we're looking from and
work directly with that
that's called our view to work directly
with our view and then shift that and
once the that view shifts just like from
Ptolemies earth centric to Copernicus
heliocentric view once the shift when
where you at once a view from where
you're at shifts then the whole
constellation falls into place and you
can see clearly where you need to be you
can see clearly what the next steps are
you can see clearly there's a clarity of
purpose and alignment with passion your
energies aligned and the future really
starts to come into shape in a very
concrete way so but for our summer
program this summer at the eight-week
program this is the core feature of our
practice is to take what you bring to
the conversation what's important to you
what are your critical and significant
questions and collectively work that
into this practice of working directly
with the view that you're currently
holding all the complexity of that view
and shift it into something that's much
more elegant and beautiful and
manageable and work or keable and
inspirational to get that insight to
shift your view so that's a big
difference that all the Lord insight
Center can make in your life it's so
practice we've been developing with
groups and individuals and it's very
very powerful so I hope to see you here
this summer